I'm a lazy workaholic. I have to force
myself to do it. My demeanor would be to
do nothing. What's that mean?
>> Okay, this was shocking. So, I've been a
massive fan of Rick Rubin for probably
decades. Uh, I grew up listening to rap.
He founded one of the most important
hip-hop um record labels in his dorm
room when he was like 18 or 19. I think
he's 63 now and he's still making
incredible music. So, I've done a bunch
of episodes about him for going back
like five, six years ago for uh going
back five or six years on my other
podcast, Founders, right? So, I read
biographies about him. I read his book
Creative Act. Have you read Creative
Act?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. And so, then I had the opportunity
to meet him and then record an episode
with him and I thought, you know, I've
read his biography over and over again.
I've watched every interview with him. I
thought I kind of knew what to expect.
And that was when he said, "I'm a lazy
workaholic." You can even watch the clip
on the show where it's like this. You're
lying to me, Rick. Like, what are you
talking about? Because out of anybody in
the world that gets paid to be
themselves, you would say like Rick
Rubin's got to be towards the top of
that that list, right? And I thought he
was just completely obsessed with music.
I thought he was just obsessed and
absolutely loved his work. And his whole
point, he was just like, "No, I have to
force myself to do it. Like, I like the
act of creation. And I like finishing
the creation, but the 5 months of us
doing thousands of takes. He goes, "I
don't like that. I wake up every day and
I'm like, "Oh my, it's not like he said
the line he said." He goes, "It's not
like I wake up every day." I'm like, "Oh
my god, I get to go to work today." He
goes, "Oh no, I have to go to the
studio."
>> And what was the reason I wanted to talk
to you about that was cuz like when you
put that out, I got thousands of
messages from people in all walks of
life saying, "This is exactly how I
feel. Like I love after I'm done
working. I like some parts of it, but I
feel that I have to force myself to do
it. And uh
>> Rick's hilarious because he he's like,
you know, it's a beautiful day. We
filmed at Shangala,
>> his recording studio, Malibu. And I
think I think I might have said or he
might have said he's like, I'd rather
just be, you know, out here butt naked
in the sun [laughter] instead of in the
studio.
>> There is a part of me that doesn't want
to show up for anything and I have to
overcome that every day. Yeah, that's
his that's a direct quote from him,
which is again shocking considering
because you know I understand if you're
trying to do something, you do it for a
year, maybe five years, maybe you can
you struggle through that for a few
years, but this guy has been in the same
industry, the same business, likely
doing the same trade for four decades.
And he says he's felt like that forever.
He's like now he just has a little bit
more control over his life. He was
telling me that like the first 25 years
of his career, it was essentially seven
days a week, 16 hours a day in a dark
recording studio.
>> It's tough to do if it feels like a
burden. If you have to make yourself do
that and you've got this tiny bit of
enjoyment at the end once you've shipped
the product.
>> Part of part of my like my heart sank a
little because he is like somebody
admire and you know, somebody almost
like a hero of mine and I feel the
opposite like I wake up you know and I
was like I cannot wait. right now the
the team uh we took a two week break
from the new show because the team was
in Italy. One of the team members is
getting married and it was like close to
depression. I was like I miss not being
able to podcast and have these
conversations and like just do the
things that I'm doing every day. So it's
completely opposite. It's how I felt is
how I thought Rick would have felt. So
it was like very surprising. You see
somebody is literally the best in the
world at what he does. He maintains a
singular position and he's telling you
no. It's a [\h__\h] struggle for me too.
>> What's driven him to keep going if he
dislikes the process that much? He loves
the magical act of creation. When
something is not going well and they're
they're failing and they're failing and
then failing and they're experimenting
and experimenting and then they just do
one little tweak, it's like, "Oh, now we
got it." He's like, he says he's
addicted to that that moment of creation
of figuring it out. That's what he
likes. High level problem solving.
Basically, the context window that Rick
Rubin has is bigger than anybody else's
for music. And he's just able to take
all of this stuff in and
I think you just nailed it. his and this
is something very common with anybody
who gets to the top of the profession.
You're going to notice that they have
this this encyclopedic knowledge of
history in their head.
>> So he'll talk about, you know, oh hey,
we're struggling with, you know, we're
working with uh Red Hot Chili Peppers.
We took an idea that the Beatles did 30
years earlier. Uh there's this great
documentary about his recording studio
called Shingali. I think it's a
four-part documentary. And if they're
struggling, he's got this like massive
library. And he'll just go in there.
He's like, "Hey, we don't know what
we're doing." He'll take one of the the
musicians he's working with. He'll just
pick a random book off a shelf, open to
a random page and read a paragraph and
then they'll just talk about that
paragraph. Did that spawn any kind of
thought and so yeah, he's got this
incredible knowledge in his head.
>> Chips on shoulders put chips in pockets.
So this is a quote from this venture
capitalist named Josh Wolf. And I think
about this maximum all the time. It
reappears throughout entrepreneurship
history. It still reappears for people
building companies today. This comes
from the founder of Apploven, this guy
named Adam. Adam is probably the best
founder no one's ever heard of. He's
running like a $170 billion market cap
company. They're going to print
something like $6 billion in cash this
year and he's got 400 employees. And
Adam hires the the the context of this
discussion we were having is that he
won't if you just have like this normal,
you know, you you grew up wealthy, you
went to great prep schools, you got into
Harvard easily. Like he doesn't hire
those kind of people. He looks for
dysfunctional people that have something
to prove. His number two is this guy
named Raph. And Raph uh has worked for
Adam over half of his life. Raph is a
high school dropout. Started working for
Adam when he was 17 years old. Uh got
kicked out of his house, had to live
inside of the office. There's pictures
they've showed me where he like built
bunk beds in the office. He's now the
second largest uh shareholder in App 11.
So the kids in his early 30s, the guy's
in his early 30s and he's got, you know,
five or six billion worth of Appven
stock, for example. And when you hear
Adam and people like this talk about,
hey, these are the people I want to
hire. They have something to prove.
They're very hungry. They tend to work a
lot harder. They're a lot smarter.
They're a lot scrappier. But then I
think what's also interesting is they're
also telling you about them. And so one
thing that that drove Adam to build his
company because like I said, it's you
know $170 billion market cap company.
When he started the company, he tried to
sell he went around to all the top VCs
in the world, tried to raise money. He's
like, I will give you a quarter of my
company. I will give you 25% of my
company for a million. That means he
valued his own company at $4 million.
Every single top VC in the world turned
him down. Then they went and funded his
competitors. And once they did that, he
goes, then it was our company goal to
drive those people out of business.
>> And you go from, you know, saying my
company's worth 4 million to 15 years
later, I took my company public. It's
now, you know, almost 200. I think the
the the top it went to is like 220
billion. And he thinks what they're
trying to do is he thinks he has a path
to like a trillion dollar company. And
he wants to do that by essentially
having this like island of misfit toys.
These people that were looked over by
other people. They failed over and over
again. Uh they would not be hired by the
big firms. It's a weird company with
full of unusual business practices. You
have to be an unusual person to thrive
in that kind of environment. And he
feels those are the best the single best
employees that you can find.
What is it that you think drives
somebody to keep going through that
situation with that chip on their
shoulder?
>> I I mean, dude, me and you have hung out
a bunch. We've had crazy conversations
off very personal conversations. Uh,
some of which we should have recorded.
We were talking before here. I mean, you
have this
>> like you know, you grew up workingass,
this like random part of the world. Uh,
I think I obviously have this too. Um,
I don't
I think like both you and I and I think
Adam fits into this and I think Rapha
just talked about it's like the the
feeling I had is like man I was just
like born in the wrong spot like this is
not this this is not my peer group. This
is not going to be the destiny of my
life. Like this is why me and you read
so much why we listen to podcasts why
we're like huge into you know
self-education and self-improvement.
It's just like, well, this is the
station I was born into, but like I can
the world is very malleable, and if I go
after something with like maximum effort
and drive and intensity, like I can
change the world around me. I remember
the first time we recorded, I think you
were still living in the UK. This is
probably like four years ago, and then
you just gave me this tour of this
crazy, insane studio you've built out.
It's like, you did this exact thing
yourself. It's like I didn't like my
life, so I'm going to use that chip on
my shoulder as fuel to prove that I'm
not subject to these circumstances. I
can actually influence this.
>> There's a Kanye West clip. Have you seen
this before? It's him on the Breakfast
Club talking about 2013 versus 2023.
>> No, I'd love to see it though,
>> dude. It's not quite the edit that I
wanted cuz a lot of the B-roll and stuff
of all of the [\h__\h] that he did. But this
is this is [\h__\h] spectacular. the
interview for me from 10 years ago.
Everybody [music] says I love that
interview. People didn't love it back
then though cuz I was [music] speaking
to the future. I'm 10 years ahead
mentally and I'm trapped in today's time
and every now and then I crack you a
smile for 2013 but I'm cracking you a
frown [music] for 2023 and I'm focused
on what it's going to be. Just mark my
words as I'm Kanye West. You seen my
execution. [music]
Did I not become the biggest rock star
on the planet? Did I not influence all
[music] musicians? Did I not go and get
the exact girl that I wanted? Did I not
start my family? That I not [music]
ruffle the feathers of two presidents?
Did I not get a chance to operate work
for my idol? Did [music] I not make
Louis Vuitton? Did people not line up at
the Yeezy store? Did I not make the
college dropout? Late registration,
graduation, 808s, [music]
blueprint one, blueprint three, watch
the throne, cool summer, [music] and
Yees. If you like it, then that.
>> I love that. It's funny you bring that
up because have you seen the documentary
on Netflix where this guy's poor? He's
living in a shitty apartment in Newark,
New Jersey at the time, and he has a
filmmaker follow him around as he's
trying to sell his beats in New York
City. Have you seen this?
>> It's in terms of like
>> biggest bet on himself,
>> the hero's journey. In fact, I
transcribed I think the first two
episodes of that documentary. You could
skip the third episode is like the
perfect illustration of this idea like
that we talked about last time I was on
the show. belief comes before ability.
>> Mhm.
>> And you see like they just he's he's
walking to the train and he's practicing
his Grammy acceptance speech. He's never
even wrapped a bar. He does not have a
signal a single out. It was so good that
I was transcribing those two episodes
and I was going to make it into a
founders episode and then he did that
like huge anti-Semitic rant. I was like,
"Oh, I'm just going to put this
>> We'll shut that for a while. We'll wait
till he comes back around."
>> Yeah, you're right, dude. I mean, this
is the the topic that's probably the
most likely thing that I write my book
about will be the lonely chapter. And
it's moving from a place where you don't
belong to one where you feel like you
do. And it's
you're so developed that you no longer
fit in with your old set of friends, but
you're not yet sufficiently developed
that you build the new ones. And you're
stuck in this messy middle, and you're
thinking, well, the the Rocky montage is
three and a half minutes in the movies,
but it's been four years for me. And
what the [\h__\h] going on? You've got all
of this doubt and it's tainted by
uncertainty about what the future holds
for you and everybody that's around you
doesn't understand what you're doing or
doubts what you're doing or actively
stops you from doing the thing that
you're doing. And it's a selection
criteria. Very few people are born into
an environment that is supportive for
rapid change and growth because people
don't like that. It feels like chaos. It
feels like uncertainty. And if you make
a lot of changes, it throws into quite
harsh contrast all of the ways that I'm
not changing. If you grow a lot, that
means that my lack of growth is
potentially on me. It's the same reason
that in the black pill and the incel
community, ascending, as in being liked
by women, is one of the um it's you
become outcast if that happens because
you're not a true cell. You're a fake
cell.
One of the reasons for that is if you
can get laid or if you can get a phone
number from a girl, maybe I can too. And
hope with disappointment is way more
painful than apathy with acceptance. And
uh yeah, chips on shoulders put chips in
pockets.
>> Do you like it's funny, you never know
where you're going to resonate with.
[snorts] Um and I think the out of all
the think about how many short form
videos we we've probably consumed in our
lives like I don't know tens of
thousands. And there's like this one
minute maybe 30 second clip of Shia
Labuff. I don't even I don't I'm
pronouncing his name. the actor Shia,
whatever his name is.
>> And he said something where it's just
like when me, you and George were
talking right before we started
recording. Uh you'll you'll feel this
like when you read, you know, somebody
else's like story of book, you're like,
"Oh, I feel like I'm reading about
myself. Like this is exactly how I
feel." And he was talking about he's
another person that chips on shoulders
put chips in pockets. He was talking
about he's like, "Hey, I don't care what
you think." He was he's like because he
goes, "I grew up in an environment where
there's like no support." So what the
defense mechanism and the tool that he
used was he's like I had to convince
myself that my opinion about what I was
doing in life my life was the most
important opinion and he literally and
he would cut everybody else out of his
life that gave him like counter evidence
that hey you're not going to make it as
an actor. Go back and watch the
documentary on Kanye. There's like there
was nobody around him that he was not
going to keep you in your life if you
said hey just be a producer. There's
that was a great Kanye clip that you
played. One that I watch all the time.
It's a minute long. It's called Kanye
West spazzing out. This is before he put
out his first album. And he's cl he's he
the clip starts he's like hitting his
hands. He goes, "Don't compare me to any
other producer rapper." Because at the
time there was other people that started
in production and didn't started rap.
And he went over and over again. He
goes, "Hey," he goes, "You understand at
one point my beats were whack, dog." He
goes, "I taught myself how to make hot
beats." These are, this is his words
now. He goes, and the same thing with
rapping. He goes, "I don't know how to
rap. I'm going to teach myself how to do
it. That growth mindset and he goes and
the clip ends and the great thing goes
and I have a leg up because I hear my
beats first.
>> The mind is a powerful place and what
you feed it can affect you in a powerful
way. Okay, so that is a line from
another rapper, this guy named NF, who's
one of my uh favorite rappers. And that
reappears throughout not only the books
I read, like all these books on
history's greatest entrepreneurs that
I've read for my other podcast, but when
I start sitting down and talking to, you
know, some of the best entrepreneurs in
the world, like I do for the new show,
this came from Toby Luke, founder of
Shopify, and it was the most surprising
conversation I may have ever had in my
entire life. Okay? Because you go in
like if you've never met somebody
before, you're gonna there's gonna be
some kind of like typ cast, right? It's
like you got this German engineer who
built a $200 billion company and this
one of the most successful technology
platforms that ever been created and he
started as a by himself with a single
laptop in his wife's childhood bedroom
because he had no money and they
literally had to be supported by his
wife's family at the time. And so you
think this guy's German engineer, he's
going to be super analytical. And then
you talk to him and he's all about
intuition and vibes for lack of a better
word. And his whole thing was just like,
well, the way you view yourself is very
important and you should know that you
can change the way you view yourself.
And what you tell yourself, the inner
monologue that you have is very
important. And so for a long time, he
told himself that I'm afraid I'm I'm
afraid of public speaking. I'm afraid of
it. I'm bad at it. That's just who I am.
And what he would do, again, this sounds
like Willy Fufu nonsense, but it
actually works. He's like every day for
10 minutes for I think a week or two or
however long it took, he would sit there
and write 100 times. I love public
speaking. I love public speaking. I love
public there's nothing else to that.
Just the same positive affirmation and
he was brain literally brainwashing
himself to now he's phenomenal on
podcast. He can he can give a
presentation in front of his thousands
of employees. He can go on stage. He
loves public speaking. He literally
changed his brain. And so I think this
is really important on uh not only like
the people you keep around you. We just
touched on it's like dude I don't have
any money in my life that's like
pessimistic or negative like these kind
of people like they're cut out root in
STEM. Uh I my information diet is like I
read old books and I talk to smart
interesting people. The way that I
choose who I talk to is like the
conversation we had. How do I feel after
I just had an hour or two hour
conversation with Chris? [\h__\h] alive.
Excited. Like you had George's idea
about sofa friends and treadmill
friends.
>> You should Yeah. Repeat it though.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Just that after some people
you feel like you need to go and lie
down on a sofa and stare at a ceiling
for a while and after spending time with
other people you feel like you want to
go and run on a treadmill. The
postcontent clarity or postnut clarity
the equivalent of for after you watch a
piece of content on the internet from a
creator that keeps on popping up in your
feed or that maybe you've subscribed to
for a while or not so long of a while.
How do you feel after that? Do you want
to go outside and ring your mom? Do you
feel like you can achieve more? Do you
feel like the world is against you or
for you? Do you are you bitter and
looking for enemies or are you positive
sum and thinking about abundance? And
again, I think people are just way too
cavalier on what they put in their mind.
So like I'm just going to sit on X and
I'm just going to the algorithm is going
to push whatever it wants into my brain
and I'm going to sit there and receive
it. That's crazy to me. It's like you're
influenced by everything. You should be
very careful. The mind is a powerful
place. What you feed it affects you in a
powerful way.
>> You just like you don't put [\h__\h] in your
body if you care about your health and
the way you look. Like why wouldn't you
do that same thing for your mind?
>> Yeah. Someone once described modern
wisdom as spirulina for your soul in a
sea of fast food for your amydala. And I
was like yeah that's quite nice.
>> But okay so this ties to I think a large
theme of the discussion that we can have
today and a lot of discussions we have
in the past. It's like man you get one
life. You get one life. You have to do
some I I do think work for most humans
is like a source of meaning at least for
you and I. It's like I feel really
freaking good about the podcast I make
and the information I put out there and
like what I'm putting out there. And to
to play on this other end where it's
just like you're just like junk food for
the mind. It's like you this is your one
shot at life and this is what you did.
You have to feel good when you hear
stuff like that. I really think if
people could if people could go to the
end just for a moment. If they could
speedrun two alternate universes
forward. one where they did the
equivalent of selling their soul and
getting all of the success but not
resonating with what it was that they
did or speedrunning it in a way that
meant that the success came but it came
without effort and without personal
sacrifice and without like uh investment
of yourself and the other one where you
had 50% or 10% of the success but it was
spoken truly from you like I I' I've
been around enough people who have done
something that resonates and that they
love who are way less successful than
others that have got bigger platforms.
But the people that have got big bigger
platforms are way more miserable, way
more miserable because they don't they
don't feel it. Like you don't want to be
you don't want to achieve success. You
want the feeling that being successful
gives you and you can get the first
without getting the second if you're not
careful. You can achieve success and not
feel it. Especially if you do something
that you don't really care about. I
would I would say though like the
benefit to tie to tie this together is
like the benefit of reading old books is
like I just finished rereading this
biography uh of Joseph Poller from the
Puler Prize and he built one of the most
successful media businesses and he was
doing around this time of the civil war.
That's how he got to America. He was a
very poor he was a Hungarian immigrant
by the time he's 17 years old. his
father and seven out of his eight
siblings have died and from like disease
and so he has to come fight in the Civil
War because he has no money and there
was a bunch of wealthy American
businessmen that were trying to to seed
the Union army and they figured hey
we'll get a bunch of European men say if
we'll pay for your passage over here and
if you survive you'll get x amount of
money you could you start a new life in
America that's how polish got to start
>> now he built uh his media at the time
was he had two of the most successful
newspapers in the world including the
most successful newspaper in the world
now the negative part of his and where
he kind of laundered his reputation by
seeding the Puliter Prize and the
Pulitzer School of Journalism is that he
also is credited with the invention of
yellow journalism. All yellow journalism
is now is like exactly what we see when
we open up Instagram or X. It's just
sensationalism, violence, sex, things
that just speak that for hundreds of
years, thousands of years have peaked
human interests. So, not that it's good
for you, it's just that you're
interested in it. It's
>> compelling. So if you read this book,
cuz I always get shipped because people
are always like, "Hey, like you don't I
don't know anything about current
affairs. Like I don't pay attention to
news. I don't read newspapers. I don't
look at any of that stuff." And so I get
a lot of stuff about this. And my thing
is like if you just read Joseph Polish's
biography and William Rand Purse who
copied his career off Puler like I did
and you'll see the connection like why
am I doing this?
>> Like do that first and then say you
should, you know, redline this negative
information about something's happening
3,000 mi away or 5,000 mi away over and
over again for your brain. I've learned
from over a thousand podcast episodes
that the easier you make your health
routine, the more consistent you'll be.
It's like golf, right? You want to keep
it simple and not mix a bunch of pills.
You want the eye of the tiger, not the
DUI of the tiger. That's why I'm such a
huge fan of AG1. One scoop contains 75
vitamins, minerals, probiotics, and
whole food source ingredients in a
single daily drink. And now they've
taken it a step further with AG1
NextGen, backed by four clinical trials.
And in those trials, it was shown to
fill common nutrient gaps, improve key
nutrient levels in just 3 months, and
increase healthy gut bacteria by 10
times, even in people who already eat
well. Gone are the days of needing to
buy a load of pills in the gym parking
lot from some juice broy.
But if you're unsure about it, AG1's got
a 90-day money back guarantee, so you
can try it every single day for 3
months, and if you do not like it, they
will give you your money back. Right
now, you can get a free AG1 welcome kit
that includes a bottle of D3K2, an AG1
flavor sampler, and that 90-day money
back guarantee by going to the link in
the description below or heading to
drink ag.com/modern
wisdom. Speaking of poor immigrants that
come to the United States, do you know
what that cigar is? No. Do you know
where it's from? Cuba. The last factory
that's still handrolling cigars in El
Titan de Bronze Calo.
the little Havana in Miami.
>> Yeah.
>> And that's the same street that your
grandfather walked down.
>> Oh, that's funny.
>> When he arrived in Miami with nothing.
>> That's incredible.
>> Yeah, that's incredible. There's uh I
guess like it goes back to chips on
shoulders chips and pockets. It's like
uh I think one of the I have like this
weird interest, right? Like you know
this I have basically four interests.
It's history, podcast, reading, and
entrepreneurship. And the
entrepreneurship thing is really really
important to me because like you said
like my grandfather was a poor
uneducated person in Cuba. He was 38
years old. He had a a newborn son which
is my father. He had two jobs. He was a
butcher and he worked in a shoe factory.
And Castro takes over. And somehow a man
who had no education, did not speak
English and had no resources realized
what was happening and realized I have
to get me and my family out of this
country right away. And he comes to
America. He's an immigrant to America uh
and rebuilds his life. Now, he made a
bunch of bad decisions once he got here,
too, that I've learned from and avoided.
Like, I didn't ever go to prison like he
went to prison. But that one decision,
I'm always fascinated by this because
like that one decision of a man that I
don't remember meeting cuz he died uh
when I was really, really young. So, I
have no memory of him. It's like
literally changed the trajectory of my
life. And one of the most important
things about growing up in South Florida
as a son of a Cuban immigrant is I would
constantly 9, seven, 10 years old meet
people that came over here on rafts. I
was like, "This is such a weird thing.
It's like that's a one-way trip. Where
are the Americans going to the end of
Miami Beach and putting their kid on a
raft and hoping you could get to Cuba?
So, I kind of inherently understood that
I was born into a very special
environment. No control of I didn't make
that decision.
>> His decision changed the trajectory of
my life. And I do think one one thing
I'm trying to do with the new show is
like, hey, I I'm very pro capitalistic.
I'm not I'm against crony capitalism. I
like people that build products and make
other people's lives better and then
spread those products and services to
more people. And as a result, they can
generate wealth for themselves, for
their employees, for for shareholders of
public companies like John Mackey,
founder of Whole Foods.
>> I've spent a bunch of time with him. Uh
we become friends. He was one of my
first guests on my new show. And his
whole thing, he he grew up in he was a
hitchhiking hippie dropping acid in
Austin where we are today, right? And
he's just like, "Hey, I think that
Safeway is poisoning us. I'm going to
make a Whole Foods grocery store,
right?" And then do that for decades.
Fast forward two decades of him just
having that idea. It's like, I just want
a place for people to shop to get
healthy food. And as a result of the
appreciation of his stock, he was
telling stories on the podcast. He's
like, these are normal people. They were
stocking shelves. They were checking you
out. They were bagging your groceries
and they got stock options. And because
Whole Foods was successful and they
played a role in that, they were able to
send their kid to college. They never
thought they'd be able to pay for
college. They were to buy a house. Those
things should be celebrated. We should
be given a platform for people to tell
these freaking stories.
>> Find a simple idea and take it
seriously.
>> Oh god. So, you even I think have made
fun of me. The fact I won't stop talking
with this guy named Todd Graves,
>> chicken guy. [laughter]
>> Okay. I have some fun I have some
hilarious stories. I don't even know if
some of these I can't tell on the
podcast uh because now me and Todd have
uh become friends. So, Todd Graves, I
think the episode I did on him was like
Todd Graves and his 20 billion chicken
finger dream.
So, this is going to take a while, but
this is worth it. So, Todd Graves has
this idea. His init initial idea is I'm
gonna remake what In-N-Out did for
cheeseburgers. I'm going to do for
chicken finger meals, right? He's like,
I'm gonna have a super simple menu. Like
very You go to Raisin Canes. You have
basically an option. Do you want three
chicken fingers, four chicken fingers,
or six chicken fingers? People are like,
"Oh, you should make a chicken finger
sandwich." Okay, that's fine. I'll take
two pieces of bread and put my chicken
fingers on it. There's your chicken
finger sandwich. It's the the the He's
been running these businesses for 30
years. The menu has not changed in 30
years. He's like, "Oh, In-N-Out is
successful in California. Why can't I be
successful in He started in Louisiana in
Baton Rouge in LSU was his first uh was
his first restaurant. Just selling one
item but doing it better than anybody
else just like In-N-Out tries to be the
best hamburger, you know, than anybody
else when when Harry Snder uh founded
the company." And that idea of find a
simple idea and take it seriously is is
a maxim from Charlie Mer who's a hero of
mine who I talked about the last time I
was on your show. And what you'll what
Charlie spent six decades, seven decades
studying is he wanted to study extreme
business success. And what he realized
is like oh what we find in business and
I would say in life because me and you
were doing this with podcasting is the
winning system all often time goes
ridiculously far minimizing or
maximizing one or a few variables. M all
the people that we talked about, all the
people I've had on my show, all the
successful entrepreneurs that you you
that you'll talk to our our study, it's
like you realize they have very simple
businesses, even if what they're doing
is super complex. Like what's more more
complex about shooting a rocket and
landing it. But if you read about Elon,
he's like all he talks about is
simplifying, taking the idea very
seriously, deleting, reducing
complexity. So Todd Graves, his whole
thing was like, well, I'm going to sell,
his original idea was, I'm going to sell
Chicken Fingers better than anybody
else. Uh, and I'm going to do it to
drunk college kids. That's what he
thought was the total addressable market
that he had. And then he realized, so he
thought, I'm going to be able to sell to
you when you're out drinking, but he was
also open during the day. He starts
getting busy during the day. And because
he just focused on doing one thing and
doing it better than anybody else is if
you wanted the best chicken fingers,
you're just going to go to him. And so
even when he breaks down like he's got
like three or four moving parts on the
on the menu. It's like the chicken
fingers, it's the coleslaw, it's the
Texas toast, it's the fries, there's
nothing else. And then he doesn't
separate himself from the customers. So
like you could draw he's got 900 when I
talked to him a few months ago uh on my
show. He had 915 stores all owned, no
franchises, by the way. He was growing
faster in year 30 than he'd ever in his
history. So he's adding like another
hundred. How old is he? 52. No, no. He's
53 now because he started the company
was 23 years old and you you can drive
into a Raising Gaines and place an order
and everyone and Todd Gra is the one
giving you the order. He his his
business card says fry cook, cashier,
CO. So sometimes he's handing you the
order out of the drive-thru, sometimes
he's in the one like literally dumping
the chicken into the oil and doing it
because there's no separation between
him and his customer.
>> And his idea was just like, well, it's
it's served in boxes, right? He goes,
"As long as that box that I give the
customer is the best box they ever get,
they'll just keep coming back and back
and back." And because he'll never sell
the company, the reason I say it's a $20
billion chicken figure is because he
owns over 90% of the company. It's
valued at least $20 billion. He's
rejected multiple multiple billions of
dollars in acquisition offers. He says,
"I can't sell it." because he believes,
this is going to sound crazy, but he
truly believes that that God put him on
this earth to be good at chicken
fingers. And he's building this business
so he can build a lot of wealth and then
help people. And so he does a ton of
charity work, supports a lot of people,
and that's what he does with his money.
One of my favorite stories about
billion-dollar ideas. Uh Joe Hudson, his
daughter came bouncing down the stairs
after he'd been talking about businesses
for a while, over the last week. He was
a VC for a good while, raised, I think,
maybe hundred million dollars over his
career. and his daughter came bouncing
down the stairs and she said, "Um, I I
finally got it. I've got my billion
dollar idea." He says, "Oh my god, it's
it's a it's a an idea that you think is
worth a billion dollars." She says, "No,
no, that that's what I I didn't think
that's what it was." No, I've got an
idea that I wouldn't sell for a billion
dollars.
>> Isn't that cool?
>> Yeah.
>> It's such a better way to frame a
billion dollar idea.
>> Yeah.
>> What is something that you would do that
you could build that you wouldn't sell
if somebody offered you a billion
dollars? I I get a lot of [\h__\h] for this
in um because obviously a lot of
entrepreneurs listen to both my shows.
And listen, it's none of my business
what you do. I'm not concerned with
other what other people do for their
lives. I don't give advice. I I just
like build the life that I want to
build. But I'm not interested in like
start, scale, sell. And in some cases,
like I've had good friends of mine, so
they know it's a joke. They'll call me
like, "Hey, I sold my company." I'm
like, "Oh, sorry to hear that." Because
it's like what the whole point in my
opinion is like you want to get to your
last company. You want to get to the
idea that you want to what did I say
when I was on your show last time that
if you love what you do your exercise
should be death.
>> Like I just got done saying I get sad
when I don't podcast. It sounds [\h__\h]
ridiculous to a lot of people but like I
took two weeks off of not having these
conversations. My life is deficient.
Some people do grow. Some people have
phases and periods. I loved running
nightclubs for a while. Not going to
live running nightclubs forever. And
that was time. There was a time and a
place for that to happen. Uh everybody
goes through periods. Now, some people
manage to land on the thing which is an
infinite game for them and also fits
their personality across time as they
age and mature and change. But I would
say and that that's the key all the
experiences that you had you you
couldn't I think you use the word
speedrun all the time. You couldn't
speedrun that. You have to go I was 32
years old before I found my path. It was
another five and a half years before it
was be able to pay my bills.
>> Like some people Kobe Bryant found it at
13. Could you imagine how crazy that is?
Like finding your life's work that
early. I read this the bunch of
biographies on the founder of Cadillac,
Henry Leland. He found a Cadillac when
he was 60. He found a Lincoln Motors
when he was 70. Took him 60 years to
find his path.
>> That's the point. It's like there's not
like a time you have to do it by, but
all these experiences should in my
opinion should be getting you to the
thing where it's just like it's not
about a dollar amount. It's not about an
acquisition. It's not about a sale. It's
like you literally I love this so much
you couldn't pay me to stop.
>> Yeah. The loudest boos come from the
cheapest seats. Making mistakes is the
privilege of the active. So, I had this
incredible conversation with Dana White
and I I've been a massive fan of the UFC
for a decade. Um, but even a maybe even
a bigger fan of Dana to the point where
like I'll watch the press conferences,
his press conferences that he does,
they're usually like 20 30 minutes long
after fights of the fights I didn't even
get to see. He's just a phenomenal
communicator. And one of the things I
most admire about him and his life
stories, one I I I I think it's very
important like the way he is on camera
when you're watching press conferences
or on a podcast. He is exactly there is
no difference between the person you're
seeing and the person and interacting
with him in private which is really uh I
think really admirable and fascinating
personally fascinating to me. But what
you real realize about him is, man, he's
like, you know, he built the largest
combat organization in the world and
he's got tens of millions, maybe 100
million followers throughout all
different platforms. And he just gets so
much [\h__\h] about the way he's running his
business. And so you sit down with him
and the loudest boos come from the
cheapest seats. That's from this guy
named Russ who you had on your podcast.
That that episode was excellent, by the
way.
>> I love Russ too. actually just talked
about him a bunch on this episode I just
did with Steve Stout because Steve
Stout's done a bunch of phenomenal
interviews with Russ as well. But what
you realize about like Dana and really
anybody's like if you're going to do
something in the world, it's like Dana
could put on a fight like the fight he
just did at the White House. That card
was incredible, right?
Five fights. I think it's the only time
in UFC history was five knockouts.
There's still people complaining. It's
still you should have done XYZ, you
shouldn't have done this, you should
have done that. It's like and his whole
thing is he just like cuts all that
stuff out. And the the second part of
that quote where it's like making
mistakes is a privilege privilege of the
active. He on the episode and in other
interviews he'll talk over and over
again. It's like oh yeah like I [\h__\h]
that up or I made this mistake. It's
like if you're going to do anything it's
refraraming the mistake is not oh it's
something to avoid. It's like yeah that
means I'm trying.
>> It's very high trust. It's one of the
best things that you can do as an
employee. If you mess up own it as
quickly as possible. Yeah I [\h__\h] it.
when someone starts to hedge and cajul.
Even when Dana got pinned for that
situation with him and his wife in the
nightclub immediately he just took it on
the chin and I think that you can tell a
lot about somebody by what happens when
they're backed into a corner socially
like that. He just owned it like so he
so after we recorded so he's got this
insane setup in his office I should talk
about. So, he's got his office, right,
which is in has like all these crazy art
and like uh like little pieces from his
his career memorabilia
and these crazy quotes on his uh his
walls, which I'll get to in one second.
Then the other side, he's got this
insane like professional
like professional um sports team level
gym that only he and his friends work
out in. And then the other side of the
record, he's got a bar because he loves
smoking cigars, drinking whiskey, and
then he has entrepreneurs come in every
day. I think he took like I forgot what
the number like over a hundred meetings
maybe 200 meetings last year of
entrepreneurs coming in. He loves
entrepreneurship more than he loves
fighting. Yeah.
>> And he just like gives him advice.
Sometimes he does investments. He just
like wants to [\h__\h] and like hang out
with people building companies. He's
just like obsessed with that.
>> But so we spent a bunch of time
afterwards and he's showing me
throughout his office and he goes, "You
might have heard of this little dust up
I had with my wife." I'm like, "Yeah,
I'm familiar." [laughter] And so he
goes, "After that happened, I put that
on the wall." And right when you're
walking out of his office, it says, uh,
"May God have mercy on my enemies
because we won't or I won't." [laughter]
>> There's a a clip that I just sent to
Jared. It's my favorite Dana clip.
>> You can bet against me. Bet against me.
Tell me it's not going to happen. Tell
me it's going to fail. I [music] love
it. I love every minute of it.
>> Okay. So, there's a reason on the you me
and you were talking about the episode I
did with Dana before this and I kept
bringing up Todd Grace because like when
I sit across from somebody, I I have
this thing where it's like natural
pattern matching. So, like Dana is
talking, I'm like, "Oh, that's kind of
like like Rockefeller did or Henry Ford
did or like and I kept getting Todd
Graves vibes." Because Todd Graves said
the exact same thing where he's just
like, "I need people to tell me that I'm
going to fail." And he's like, I just
use it as fuel and energy that I love
people telling me they can't that I
can't do like what I want to do. And
Dana is the same way. Dana has another
great quote uh that I was watching when
I was prepping for the episode where
he's just like uh he goes, "I'm the
world's best friend, and if you want to
be friends, we can do that. But if you
want to be enemies, I can do that, too."
>> [laughter]
>> Wow.
>> [\h__\h] That's good.
>> Yeah, he's really really good. I could
talk to I mean I told him I was like,
"Listen, I'm just going to if it's cool
with you, I'm going to drop in with this
film crew every like six months because
I could talk to him an hour over and
over again. The guy never runs out of
stories." The funniest thing that's ever
been said on my podcast came from Dana
White. It really pisses him off because
if you think about how much struggle
went into to building UFC into what it
is today, it's like they bought it
almost bankruptcy for $2 million. They
dumped another $40 million into it. This
goes back to what we were just talking
about. Like you love it so much that
they couldn't pay you to stop. They lost
money for like seven years. He wasn't
making any money. And he tells this
great story of his partner uh one of the
brothers is the first year they get into
the black meetings they're making
profit. They're writing out like all the
revenue on the board. And Dana's like,
"What does that say?" And he goes,
"Saids you're going to make a million
dollars this year." It's like, "Wow,
that's incredible." Dana's a
multi-billionaire now. Like multi
multi-billionaire now. But he was just
happy just to make a million dollars
after seven years of failing. He's like,
"If I just do that, I could do this
forever."
>> Before we continue, most people in their
30s are still training hard. Their
protein is dialed in. They sleep better
than they did in their 20s. Discipline
is not the issue, but recovery feels
somewhat different. Strength gains take
a little longer. The margin for error
starts to shrink. And that is why I'm
such a huge fan of timeline. You see,
mitochondria are the energy producers
inside of your muscle cells. As they
weaken with age, your ability to
generate power and recover effectively
changes even if your habits stay strong.
Mitoure from timeline contains the only
clinically validated form of urethylene
A used in human trials. It promotes
mphagy, which is your body's natural
process for clearing out damaged
mitochondria and renewing healthy ones.
In studies, this supported mitochondrial
function and muscle strength in older
adults. It's not about pushing harder.
It's about actually supporting the
cellular machinery underneath your
training. If you care about staying
strong into your 30s, 40s, and 50s and
beyond, this is foundational. Best of
all, there is a 30-day money back
guarantee, plus free shipping in the US,
and they ship internationally. And right
now, you can get up to 20% off by going
to the link in the description below or
heading to timeline.com/modernwisdom
and using the code modernwisdom at
checkout. That's
timeline.com/modernwisdom
and modernwisdom a checkout. Successful
people listen. Those that don't listen
don't last long. Okay, so this is
shocking because if people know that's a
quote from Michael Jordan. So if you
ever seen The Last Dance, people think,
"Oh, Michael's this like tyrant. He's
this dictator. He thinks he knows better
than anybody else." And uh there's this
great book called Michael Jordan in the
life. It's like 700 pages long. Uh it's
by this guy named Roland Lazby. And I've
read that book twice. It it
fundamentally changed my life. And in
that that that I found that quote in
that book. And we realize like, no, no,
Michael's a sponge and all he wants is
useful information that's going to help
him accomplish his goals. And so a lot
of this, this applies to business. It
was like, I went to Ed Catmill's house
to record a podcast. Ed Catill is the
founder of Pixar, right? Pixar has made
they invented the the first computer
animated film. They make some of the
best films for families and for kids and
for even adults that that watch it. And
he worked with Steve Jos longer than
anybody else. He worked with Steve for
24 consecutive years and he speaks a lot
about it. He's like the the the way he's
Steve is described Steve Jobs described
in the media compared to the person I
knew. It's not the same person. So he
always tells these stories and ads this
this color and he goes, "Hey, uh Pixar
was a public company for 10 years before
Disney acquired it for like $7.6
billion." In that 10-year period, this
is Ed telling me the story now. Steve
fired two members of the board of
directors from Pixar. What most people
don't know is why he fired them. And so
I asked Steve why he fired him. He goes,
"Well, they those two people, they never
disagree with me." And so therefore, if
they never disagree with me, they're not
adding any value to the company.
>> It's like successful people listen,
those that don't listen don't last long.
He what Steve understood, what Michael
Jordan understands, what all these
people get to talk with professional
understand. It's like there's no upside
in being wrong. And so it doesn't matter
if you give me you you're the reason I
started doing video podcasts. You
remember having this conversation years
ago? You like you, we don't have to like
>> you're [\h__\h]
Exactly. So, it's like I could have been
like, "Oh, what does Chris know?" Well,
he's got the eighth biggest in the
world. Maybe he knows some [\h__\h] Maybe I
should benefit from the fact that I get
access to him
cuz he's not doing it to like criticize
him. You're like, "Hey, you could be
doing better here. You held me
accountable. It's like you can you
should be doing this. You can do doing a
better job here." I think people get
confused a lot of the time when it comes
to taking feedback, taking criticism and
they assume that uh you know committing
yourself to one thing, being on this
path, disregarding the chip on the
shoulder. They incorrectly pattern match
or they they they ignore advice and
think that it's self-belief and that's
pretty dangerous because you're just
stuck in local maxima there. Like you're
never going to reach outside of that.
And uh yeah, I I think an awful lot
about
looking for humans who are able to
update their worldview like um strong
opinions loosely held uh as opposed to
loose opinions strongly held, which is
what most people have. They haven't
really arrived there with conviction and
vigor. They've just kind of tumbled
backward. They've uh sliding not
deciding into whatever their worldview
is. There's there's actually an
interesting story um in one of these
books I read where uh Charlie Munger
when he was trying to convince you of
something he would first state the best
counterargument
and what that tell you after you know
he's very verbose and he would talk for
probably like 30 40 minutes before he's
going to let you talk. I had dinner with
him and uh I'd say he spoke 99% of the
time which is good. He was has all the
information. What the hell am I going to
say? But uh what I thought was
interesting is like what does that
imply? means he thought about this so
much that he could start with the best
counterargument and then essentially
rebut that counter-argument and say why
he believes something different and I
think that's like an excessively
valuable skill. I've never even heard of
anybody else doing that.
>> Mhm. Wise people don't solve problems,
they avoid them.
>> No, wisdom is prevention. That is lit.
So that's a munger quote. Wisdom is
prevention. And uh he had a this is the
experience of when I went and had dinner
with him and um this what you realize is
like you know any if you live long
enough I think he has another quote he's
like if you live long enough bad shit's
going to happen to you it's like
inevitable and you read his early life
and it's like he had the worst possible
thing that could happen. He was going
through a divorce. His nine-year-old son
uh had leukemia before it was curable.
And so his nine-year-old son's like
literally wasting away and he has to
like watch his son die slowly and he
would leave the hospital and like walk
around the streets of Pasadena just ball
crying his eyes out. He's like probably
35 maybe 38 years old when this is this
is happening. And yet you spend time
when you realize like he is just like
nothing can face him. He's like problems
are inevitable. And his whole thing was
like well it's you're not smart because
you solve problems. You're smart or
you're wise because you avoid them. And
so the advice that he gave us was like
if you just focus on being around really
really great people, like a handful of
really great friends. You know, you
don't need many. There's probably a
limit to how many you could have. Maybe
four or five really like people you're
going to do life with for your entire
life. You know, they love you. They're
high quality people. They're not shitty
people. He has this other side of this
is another Charlie Marrow. He says most
he's like uh most people are rat poison.
He's like there's a lot of just evil and
lowquality people out there. You should
avoid them. So you build relationships
with great people, people you love and
you can do life with. And then you find
great work. And once you find the great
work, you stay in that great work. You
don't jump around like you do that for
the rest of your life. And by
surrounding yourself with great people
and having work that you feel is great
and beneficial to the world, that avoids
that eliminates most of the problems
that are under your control. And then
life will still throw up problems that
are outside of your control. Your kid
gets sick, you get cancer, whatever the
case is. But the the the smart thing is
to is not to solve the problems. The
smart thing is to prevent them from
occurring ever.
>> Yeah. There's a an insight that it's far
easier to date somebody who compensates
for your shortcomings than it is to fix
them. That you are the sort of person
that likes to go to bed early and you've
decided to get into a relationship with
someone that wants to go out partying
until 3:00 in the morning. Maybe your
9:00 p.m. bedtime is a personal failing
because you feel like you need to have
more control over your life than you
actually do. Maybe it would be
beneficial for you to work through that
in some way and and loosen up and you
could go to bed at 11 o'clock and 12:00
or something like that.
Or you could just get into a
relationship with somebody who
compensates for your shortcomings and
he's like, "Actually, do you know what
it is? I'm not going to make you feel
insecure about that thing. I want to go
to bed at 9:00, too."
so many of the situations that we end up
having to we have basically a
frustration budget in life every single
day and it gets sapped out of you by all
of the different interactions. Let's say
uh you're going to dinner and your
friend that you're hanging out with is
just like really annoying and every
single time you go for dinner you're
super annoyed by them and then the next
morning you wake up and you've got to
deals with some real things at work that
you can't get away from or that's part
of a mission. You're like, I have less
in the tank to be able to deal with this
issue because of the situation I went
through last night or because of the
fact I had to stay up till 3 in the
morning because the girl wanted to go
and watch some [\h__\h] DJ in some
nightclub or whatever and now I'm tired
and I didn't even want to go, but I did
it because, you know, I'm going to
compromise. It's really important to
compromise.
Wisdom is prevention. Like just avoiding
problems altogether where you can like
problems are inevitable and they're
going to come and smash you in the face.
choosing like there's no nobility in
meaningless suffering. There's nobility
in meaningful suffering, but there is no
nobility in meaningless suffering. And I
would say like there's a great uh uh
quote in Spanish that that'll translate.
It's like uh this person will drown in a
cup of water. And this is what I mean
like the first part of that is before
you you find your life's work and and uh
like hopefully you're doing something
that makes the lives of other people's
other people's lives better. It's like
you have to ruthlessly edit who gets
access to you. Like the first episode I
ever did for the new show was Daniel,
founder of Spotify, right? And if
everybody always asked me like, "Oh, if
you had a uh if you could have like a
personal board of directors from all the
people you've read about, all the dead
entrepreneurs, who would you be?" And I
have an answer for that. And they're
like, "What about for a living? Like,
who would be your personal board of
directors be?" I was like, "I'd only
need one." And it's like Daniel, the
advice, the reason he was the first
guest is because the relationship we've
been able to build and the friendship we
able to build. It's like he's like the
wisest one of the wisest people I know.
I call him Swedish Buddha.
>> He's like he built one of the greatest
apps and technology companies in the
history of the world, right? And did an
an unbel had endure unbelievable
struggle to do so. But he's just very
wise and he he almost all of our
conversations I was just with him a few
months ago. We were racing cars outside
of Stockholm. Um, and we stayed up late
one night and his whole thing was just
like I still have notes from the
conversation. Just like he's like, "Man,
you just have to ruthlessly edit who's
around you." He's like, "You're just
like we said, like the mind is powerful
place. What you feed affection in a
powerful way." He's like,
>> especially you, you have a huge
platform. I can't imagine what your
freaking text messages or inbox look
like. Yeah. You coming on your show
could literally change some people's
lives. And so the problem is they're
going to give they're going to act in a
way to you that's not their real self.
And so Daniel's point about this was
just like, you know, if you if you feel
you're developing a friend with
somebody, have other people you trust,
then go and spend time with this person
because the way they act with you might
be different from them. But I'm telling
you, all these people, and I've built a
lot of friendships with a lot of guests
I've had on my show, the the amount of
times they have told me, it's just like
everything comes down to the quality of
people that you have around you. Your
life is your relationships. That's
another great maximum. Your life is your
relationships. If you have a bunch of
shitty people around you, like you're
going to have a shitty life. They're
going to cause drama unneededly because
they they will drown in a cup of water.
>> And if wisdom is wisdom is avoidance, is
prevention.
>> You you have I've cut a couple of these
people out of my life and you know way
less than I have to now because I've
been so like I have a very small circle.
I would say I just talk my natural
tendency is not to have a thousand
shallow relationships. It's just talk to
the same half a dozen people over and
over and over again. And when I doing
that I can be by myself. I'm very
comfortable reading a book, making a
solo podcast. Like, I don't give a [\h__\h]
I don't need to go out and like
constantly socialize and expose myself
to like the vagaries of others, people
like uh like corrosive and destructive
behavior. I'm not interested in that.
>> Create according to your own taste, not
for applause, critics, algorithms, or
market demand.
>> This is Rick Rubin. Like, you and I, we
just talked about this. We just both
read his book, Creative Act. And towards
the end of that book, he has this thing
called like the house on the mountain
test. And here's the great thing about
reading books about people and then
getting to talk to them. Like you get
you get to to go deeper. And I want to
tell you a story about James Dyson. We
can get there in a little bit. Uh I
think it's really important about this.
But what Rick Rubin's point was just
like your north star in whatever you're
doing. He the metaphor he used. He goes,
"Let's say you bought a house. It's on a
mountain. It's so so remote. No one is
ever going to see it but you." He goes,
"Do you not put in your best effort to
decorate it and to design it just like
you would want it done? Like you're the
only person that's ever going to see it.
No one's ever going to visit. What do
you do?" And the answer to that
question, that is your revealed
preference. That is what you actually
want to do. And so when you look at Rick
Rubin's career is what does he do? He
just makes the music that he wants to
listen to. He is not He says over and
over again, don't think about the
audience. Don't think about the
customer. Don't think about the end
user. like you're probably not unique.
Me and him talked about this. You're not
that unique. So if Rick Rubin likes this
song by Johnny Cash that with a guitar
and just, you know, and just this guy's
voice, what's the chance he's the only
person in the world that likes that?
Probably 10 million people that like the
same kind of music Rick Rubin likes.
Just like me and you, we talked about
this before we started recording. We
make the podcasts that we want to listen
to. We both are obsessed with podcasts.
They've made our lives benefit uh
benefit they've benefited our lives
immensely. I've learned more from
reading a podcast than I ever did in
school. Like I'm just making the stuff
that I'd want to listen to. I listen to
them before they come out.
>> Could you imagine like your life is
making a podcast and you have to listen
to it before it goes out and you don't
like it?
>> Doesn't make any sense. So I think that
that the idea of like the metaphor of
you're designing a house on the
mountain, no one else is going to see
it. You should design your life that
way, too. There's parts of your life
that you share with other people, but
there's huge swasts of it that only you
know. You should design those uh those
parts of your life same exact way as the
parts that other people see.
>> A rule of thumb for anybody that makes
things on the internet, would you
consume your own content?
If not, don't post it.
>> I was with you one time and you asked
somebody and there was a 30 second
pause.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And
after 30 seconds of
>> you know the answer.
>> What?
I'm like, dude, if it takes more than 5
seconds, the answer is [\h__\h] no.
>> Yeah.
>> Raid your own life. create a grand theft
life.
>> Okay. So, you told me before I missed
this episode of yours, but you just did
this like round table. What do you call
these round table episodes?
>> Rabbit hole.
>> Rabbit hole with Tim Urban.
>> Yeah.
>> Tim Urban like I don't know 10 years ago
wrote this crazy essay on Elon and
SpaceX and Tesla. He kind of predicted a
lot of the [\h__\h] that occurred in the
last decade. And he had this thing
called Grand Theft Life. And what he
realiz realized about Elon was like his
ability to step outside of himself. So
me and you are going through life all
the time and we're kind of like right
now I'm looking at you.
>> My view is a lot better than yours is,
right? Like you're a lot more handsome
than I am, but like this is my
experience and you're kind of get like
siloed into like this is I'm just
experiencing it as it happens, right?
And this started because Toby Luk, I'll
go back to Elon in one second. I sat
down with Toby Luke, founder of Shopify,
which again is probably my favorite
conversation that I've had on the
podcast so far. And he has this idea.
Again, he's when he says this, he's
running a $200 billion company. And he
goes, I like to take the view that a cor
I am a corporate raider. I did not start
Shopify. I do not run Shopify. I have
now extracted it from the owners and now
I'm the new owner. And the previous
management was crazy. And then I go
through and look at to every single
other thing I would change. Why do you
need to step aside? Because like if
you're just going through your
day-to-day, there's so many problems
he's not seeing. You have to step back.
in Tim Urban's uh Grand uh Grand Theft
um essay uh that he was writing on Elon.
It's like you see that Elon does that.
Me and you were talking about this
before where it's like okay if you look
at yourself as if you're playing Grand
Theft Auto like your character you play
Grand Theft Auto my
uh my character needs money so I go my
character goes does jobs now he has more
money. My character is stamina he's
running from the cops. He needs better
cardio so I take him to the gym. You
just literally say like from the
outside, me and you, and I hope you
don't cut this from the podcast, we had
we were in Hawaii together and we had
many many late night conversations about
issues with women that me and you were
both having that I swear to God if there
was a there was just a casual observer,
right? Just listening. They were just
like, "Chris, David, this is these are
simple solutions. You just can't see
them because we in like I could see what
was wrong with yours and you could see
what's wrong with mine." So this idea of
just stepping out your side and I love
the idea that again putting into
entrepreneurial terms like some guy is
now taking over my business or taking
over my life. What would he change?
>> Yes, you need to pause and you need way
to step back and go through this right
now.
>> George has got this idea where he talks
about um imagine that there was an evil
version of you, a man with a mustache.
What would he do to beat you?
>> What would another version of you
>> with the mustache do to beat you? or
that question of if you had 10 times the
agency, what would you do? But with that
situation, it's like you know where your
shortcomings, where your biggest
shortcomings lie. Like there's going to
be this person, okay, they would be way
more decisive. They wouldn't they would
uh need less certainty in order to reach
conviction because I know that I I I
spend too much time vacasillating and
flip-flopping back and forth and I I I
don't commit so quickly. And I know that
the version of me me with a mustache, he
would arrive at the outcome way quicker
because he wouldn't be doing the
flip-flopping. Or he would be more
cutthroat when it comes to um not giving
people third and fourth and sixth and
seventh chances because I keep doing
that and he keeps on burning me. That's
what he would do. And then you just go,
"Okay,
just just do that."
>> What What would your answer to that for
your own life be right now? The
decisiveness thing I think is probably
not far off. Um
my required level of certainty in order
to make big decisions is quite a high
bar and that's led to me making very few
mistakes. Like I haven't made every
business that I've started has
succeeded. Uh almost all of the projects
that I get involved in are very good.
But it also if you're not failing, it's
probably an indication that you're not
moving quickly enough
>> because you could move a a headroom for
moving more quickly is probably still
quite high and you would still end up
with a pretty good hit rate. Uh so
something like that. How about you?
I think especially the last year the
biggest mistake you get distracted
especially because like um there was
like a slow build to founders podcast.
Never like it's like I was like a frog
in boiling water cuz it took five and a
half years to break through another like
it was like eight before it was like any
substantial thing.
>> Three three and a half four for us.
>> Yeah. So like you it was that was great.
It was actually like in hindsight I
wouldn't change anything cuz this was
like oh I'm still the same person. I
don't feel any different. Yeah. Where
the new one because I had an existing
audience and it kind of like so it was
like disorienting how fast
>> my life changed. And then this is it
goes back to Daniel Ek and why he'd be
like my uh you know my sole person on a
living board of directors is uh he's
just like just stay away from the
circus. That's the advice that he would
give me over and over again. Um so the
evil version of you that's trying to
beat you with a mustache would just get
less distracted. He'd be more simple.
>> And this is what I've gone back to doing
where Daniel's advice is just like uh we
just had this phenomenal dinner in New
York and then uh he was driving me to a
friend's house and he's just like your
life is very simple, man. Jesus is like
he's like if you just sit in a room and
make podcasts and don't do anything
else, you know, obvious spend time with
your friends, take care of your health,
but like you don't have to go to [\h__\h]
dinners. You don't have to go to
conferences. He had this conference
called
>> just sit in a room and make podcasts,
says the guy that owns Spotify. You
think there might have [laughter] been a
somewhat of a uh
>> No, cuz he's he just stepped down. I
promise you it's not like No, no, no.
Cuz like my my shows are always going to
be somewhat niche. like your show will
always be 10 times bigger than anything
I do because I'm just narrowly focused
on entrepreneurship.
>> But what the advice because I remember
texting I was like, "Hey, are you are
you going to Brilliant Minds?" Which was
his conference
>> and I don't think he was there this
year. He goes he goes, "No, and e
neither should you." And that's when he
decided he goes, "Just stay away from
the circus."
>> Well, this is similar to if you do
everything, you will win.
>> No, that's okay. So, we can get to that
in one second. So, let me finish this
because I think I like that you asked
the question. And it's like really
helpful for me to now kind of do Grand
Theft Life and now step back and say
what I would do. So I was like I I have
work that I really like to do. I really
like to read books. I really like to
make podcasts. You know, I like
one-on-one conversations, maybe one. I
can't do like group stuff. I'm very
introverted. It makes me very
uncomfortable.
I think like and then I've got to figure
out like
the dating part, the girl part. But
other than that, like I think the
distraction is
>> Did you talk about something to do with
this last time that like so many of
history's greatest entrepreneurs have
been totally [\h__\h] with women? Like
they're just [\h__\h] hounds or they're
unable to hold a a relationship
together. But I don't know whether to
give them their due. I wonder whether
part of it is
less
they're bad with women and more
the
traits that make you a very successful
elite level entrepreneur, the kind that
you study
probably give you some traits that make
it difficult to be in a relationship
with you. So I wasn't expected to talk
about this but there I have some
interesting ideas. So there's this great
book that was written by Arnold
Schroinger's girlfriend. He had a he
lived with his girl when he was 21 to
26. So he was still rel again he's
dominating this weird niche of
bodybuilding but he's not the Arnold
that he's going to becoming but he's the
same person. So you see it's coming and
it's 300 pages of her just be like why
is this guy not acting normal? It's like
cuz it's Arnold. He's one of the most
driven people in the world. I could have
solved that for you in 10 seconds,
right? And the end result when I made
the episode on that book was like a su a
successful entrepreneur or anybody
chasing after somebody you need a
supportive spouse or no spouse at all.
Right? And that and that's the key
there. What I would also say is uh I've
been talking to this guy. He considers
himself like a consultant to some of the
most famous people in the world. Right?
>> And what I find interesting is like he
can essentially pattern match across
let's say a hundred of the most famous
people in the world. These are like
mainstream celebrities. This is not like
me and you, right? And he talked about
but and some of these people also happen
to be captains of industry because
Elon's one of the most famous people on
the planet. He's not one of his people
he talks to but and he goes the problem
that these people have is when you're
really successful like that you you have
an expansive personality. That's the
word that he used expansive personality
which means the more you succeed the
more you want to succeed.
>> Napoleon said this in French and you
could u translates into appetite comes
with eating. Usually you eat and you're
full. These kind of people, the more
they eat, the more they want to eat. So
his point is like these people also have
usually bad relationships because
there's a ton of infidelity, right?
Because it's just like they're expansive
and in every element of their life,
they're they're increasing their skills.
They're maybe their movie is getting
better bigger, maybe their business is
getting bigger, they're expanding. But
in this very narrow but very important
part of your life, which is like your
romantic side, you're expected to not
have those same personality traits. Now,
I don't have that issue. I am can stay
with one person at a time. Um
the the issue that you have is like
whether it's a very close friend, a
business partner, a spouse, these are
all very similar relationships like they
they look a they're very deep
partnerships and so you have to be take
your take be very careful to make sure
you're picking the right person and
>> especially you because you're handsome,
rich, super famous. Like you have I've
seen some of your dams, okay? Like you
have a [laughter]
I hope we cut in that laugh over there.
Yeah, make sure you add that in. Um,
like you have so many people trying to
get to you that want something from you.
That doesn't mean they're good for you.
And that's where you have to be careful.
That's where you have to be somewhat
paranoid. Most people have no idea where
the testosterone levels sit. But what if
I told you there was a solution?
Something that identifies low tea faster
than a high school bully and it won't
cost you all your lunch money. That's
where function comes in. gives you
access to over 160 lab tests, including
a deep dive into your full hormone
paddle. Every result is reviewed by
clinicians. Anything out of range is
flagged and you get clear explanations
with a personalized protocol with
actionable next steps. So, if
something's off, you know exactly what
to do about it. Whether you just need to
go to the gym more or you need to play
Creed louder in your car, Function will
tell you exactly where your testosterone
and everything else stands. Normally,
this level of testing would usually cost
thousands, but with function, it's $365
a year. That's $1 a day to stop guessing
with your health and start knowing. And
right now, you can get $25 off, bringing
it down to 340 bucks. So, get the exact
same blood panels that I do and save $25
by going to the link in the description
below or heading to
functionhealth.com/modernwisdom
using the code modernwisdom at checkout.
That's what discernment is, right? being
able to distinguish between good and not
good, between somebody that's got your
best interest at heart and doesn't.
>> You know, the advice I've gotten from
some of the, you know, the most
successful people in the world about
this, they're just like, make sure that
she's a good person. Like that's it.
They just have to be a good person, but
good people are few and far between. And
what I mean by good is like not selfish,
not doing this just because of what's
good, what they get out of it, and
willing to. And in many cases, dude,
Jimmy I Okay, Jimmy I got to talk about
this because this guy's the best. So
when people used to ask me, hey, you
know who who did you want to meet, you
haven't met, Jimmy I, I'd have a list
and Jimmy I would be in top three and
people like that doesn't make any sense.
Most people don't know who Jimmy is. But
one of my favorite documentaries is this
documentary called The Defiant Ones.
Have you seen this? No.
>> You got to watch it tonight. So it's a
four-part documentary. It's technically
supposed to be about the relationship,
the working partnership between Jimmy
Aine and Dr. Dre that's been going on
for decades. It is really one of the
best documentaries about
entrepreneurship and these kind of wild
personality types. Dr. Dre is a wild
boy. He is a He was a probably highly
likely a child prodigy. The best in the
world he does. Jimmy, same thing. He he
is in the music business for five
decades and has succeeded from engineer
to producer to record label executive to
building a business that's selling and
selling it for $3 billion to Apple. And
so I Jimmy was on my show. We live close
to each other. He's nice enough that I
get to hang out with him and like talk
to him on the phone and hang out with
them all the time now. And it's what's
fascinating is when you talk to these
older guys that are I think Jimmy's
probably 70 years old by now.
>> He's got more knowledge about life in
his pinky than I do in my entire body.
>> Like he's just lived through. So he's
just seen everything. And his biggest
thing was
>> he's like if you want to be successful
he's like you probably don't want to be
successful for a year for 5 years. You
want to do it for a long period of time.
And he's like I've been around some of
the most gifted talented people in the
world. He's worked with everybody from
John Lennin to Bruce Springsteen to Tom
Petty to Dr. to Dre to Eminem to
literally everybody and out of the one
he's like most people the advice he gave
me is like most people cannot handle
success.
>> Yeah.
>> You're not destroyed
by by a competitor. There's not going to
be another Chris Williamson coming in
here and out competing you in
podcasting. You're going to do if you're
going to fail, you're going to do it
yourself. And what Jimmy said, he's like
they fall into four buckets, which I
thought was interesting. Number one,
drugs. I don't do drugs. Not going to be
an issue. Like I avoid them. Alcohol.
Second one. I don't really drink. Number
three, uh, Megalomania, because
remember, he's in the music industry.
He's like, "Listen, you start out. I
mean, Kanye, I think he he I'm a huge
fan of his first four albums." I think
this is what happened some in my
opinion, what happened to him. It's
like, and Jimmy was saying, it's like
really hard that like you get on stage
every night and there's 80,000 people
telling you, screaming your name and
telling you how great you are. The
problem is to come off that stage and
then still be dad or husband or friend,
take the trash out.
>> Yeah. and and you not think and then
what happens is the reason he calls it
megalomania is because they loved you
because of the work you put in. The
megalomania thinks now you think you're
some you're not even human. You're like
some kind of like god. So therefore I
don't I just show up and it happens and
they they stop putting in the work then
it shows up on the work and then there's
death spiral. And then the fourth thing
was women and Jimmy I has been very uh
he he's like very open about this.
that's in the documentary where he his
dad was his best friend like best friend
talks every day. Jimmy was dating a
Playboy playmate and [snorts] his dad
died suddenly unexpectedly. They did not
see it coming and right after his dad
died he decided to get married and he
says on the documentary we've talked in
longer detail privately but you know
it's just like
I married the wrong person. He's very
beneficial of all the kids and he's got
great relationship with his adult kids
now. He talks to his kids every single
day. But he's just like that the wrong
woman in your life, the wrong man in in
a woman's life can literally destroy
you. And so I think that I think this is
like we could we should have an entire
podcast next time we come here. We just
talk about the stuff we've talked about
privately. [laughter]
>> Yeah. [\h__\h] me.
>> But it is it's it's a very hard part of
your life because I do consider it
almost like a drug. Like these people
don't start out, hey, I'm going to get
addicted to pills or heroin or alcohol
>> and they're smart and successful. It's
arrogant to think that wouldn't happen
to us. So that's why I think it's so
important to like talk about it.
>> Agreed. Agreed. Yeah. I had this line
from earlier this year. What you are
praised for in public, you will pay for
in private.
>> Mhm. And a lot of the time the
single-mindedness, the resilience, the
motivation, the permanent growth
mindset, the attention to detail, the
unwillingness to compromise, the
hypervigilance, the anxiety,
dedication, all of these things. In the
business world, it's called
reliability, consistency,
uh, uh, non-quititness.
Fantastic. in the boardroom can often
make you
a forgotten person around your kitchen
table. I had uh Andy Stump, Navy Seal,
on the podcast and he said, "I built
built my entire identity around being a
guy that doesn't quit." So, it made me
an amazing SEAL team member. Also made
me stay in a marriage for a decade
longer than I should have done.
>> Yeah,
>> I don't quit. Not the sort of guy that
quits. You know, there are certain
domains in which the things that you do
publicly aren't meant to be applied and
a lot of those are the ones that happen
privately. And then when public and
private begins to sort of mesh and blend
together, that's what we get with modern
social media, right? That you can't see
the distinction between the two. And and
the problem is like you're constantly
comparing like your relationship to
other people's ideal relationship, which
is very destructive. And what what I
would say about this is like you you
talk about being hyperrational. I think
you approach your business. I [\h__\h]
know a lot about your business. Like
you're very rational. I actually don't
think we should and I don't want to and
will not do in like your romantic life.
I think you have to like you should be a
little bit irrational. It is it is
definitely like a a more irrational
emotional thing. That's why I think the
advice that I keep getting over and over
again is just like make sure the person
that you're letting into your life, the
one that you have a serious relationship
with right now is just a good person
that they actually care about you that
they actually want good things for you
because it's not going to work if you
try to approach it with like a rational
mind. It is default irrational. And what
I would say this is something like um so
we we have a good friend um Sienna
Laroka.
>> Yep.
>> And one of the conversations I have I
had with her was just like what are you
lying to yourself about?
>> Yep. And this could be an entire
discussion at dinner because everybody's
lying to themselves about something and
what I didn't understand about myself,
especially until I started the new show
because I was just I was sitting in a
room by myself for a decade like talking
to myself like no one was around and I
always thought like I didn't need
anybody and like I'm a loner and like
you know other people aren't that
important to me. And I realized like no
that's a lie. Like I had just a lot of
lowquality people around me. But like if
I could have access and develop
relationships and friendships with high
quality people, that is my drug of
choice. Like I remember when I went to
record with Todd Graves, we flew into
Baton Rouge and recording the very first
Raising Canes that he built with his own
hands. He built it with his hands. It's
insane. And I remember calling a good
friend of mine. He's kind of like he's
like an older brother, like a mentor,
like a coach. Um and I called him and I
was like, "I'm in trouble." And he goes,
"Why?" I go, "Cuz I'm already addicted
to doing this. I feel like I'm high as a
kite right now. I've never done ecstasy.
I've never done MDMA. I have to imagine
this is what it feels like. I want to do
this all the time. Um, and so I guess
like what I didn't understand, what I
was lying about myself was like that
relationships weren't important to me
where
>> the truth is they're more important than
anything else. So I'm sorry to monologue
to you, but I think let me just get this
out real quick if you don't mind.
I desperately did not want to be a loser
and that's why I'm a workaholic and I've
worked full-time since I was 15 years
old because I saw up and down my family
tree. I was just [\h__\h] terrified of
winding up just like them. And this is
the chips on shoulders chips in pockets.
Like I I I'm not a strategic person. I
genuinely just throw a lot of hours and
effort. I don't think I have any
strategy.
>> Um and so I thought forever like my my
work is how I protect myself because
it's it's gives me my independence. It
allows me to build a world that I can
control because I didn't have control
when I was younger. It allows me to take
care of family members and other people
to help. And it's like it's my thing.
It's the only it's more important. If
you were asking, it's like more
important than anything in my life. And
I realized that that's a lie. Like if
you ask what's the most important thing
in my life right now, it is my
relationships. It's building and
maintaining and deepening the
relationships I have with people that
are very high quality that I love with
everything. Now, right underneath that,
my work's like bumping up against it,
but this is still my number one
priority. And I think also you'll see
for people like you, you're super driven
just like I am, you for you forgo some
professional success if you want like a
deep romantic relationship. And I would
say that's what like makes life worth
living. You should do that. You should
make the irrational choice. How do you
square that circle with the
single-mindedness that most great people
have?
>> I don't think you can. I think like
there's an eb and flow like if you look
at a snapshot of like my own life,
right? Where undoubtedly I think I would
be even more I would be more successful
if you didn't take out the huge chunks
of time to build these relationships
both romantic and friendship wise. But
that's not the kind of life I want to
live. Now I've met people like that. I
know some of these people have been on
my show. You get around them and and you
literally like where's all your friends,
dude? They're not that's not important
to them. that's not what they're going
for. They're they're playing a different
game. What I'm saying is like that's not
for me. Like I want I'm not saying a
balanced life cuz I'm definitely not
balanced, but like I relationships are
more important than my work. That's just
how I feel. Far fewer people than think
it are introverts. Like you're probably
not an introvert. Your friends just
suck. That's a that's a great way to
think about it.
>> And if you had better friends, you'd
want to hang around them. There's like
everybody has been at a dinner table and
adored the conversation and not wanted
it to end. Yeah.
>> Okay. Well, what what happened there?
Did you change for the evening? No. I
was just around people that resonate. I
was around people who I usually don't
resonate with, but for some reason, they
were really on form that night. Well,
you can just get friends that are kind
of on form all the time. And you can
also hang around with people who are
never on form. I I've had friends of
mine tell me this. It goes back to where
we were saying the mind is powerful
place. Switch your feet affect powerful
way. They're like, man, you got to be
real careful about the way you describe
yourself. And I think around this, I
kept saying, I'm introverted. um like I
I want to be alone, all this other
stuff. And this is like that's not how
you are. To your point, I think it's
more of like an energy thing. Like the
conversations we have, I leave George
Max's treadmill.
>> Yeah.
>> If you put me in a big party with a
bunch of strangers, I'm like, there's no
energy and I got to run away. So, it's
more like, am I getting energy from this
or am I very uncomfortable? Is it
draining my energy?
>> If you go to sleep on a win, you'll wake
up with a loss. So, this is actually a
Conor McGregor quote uh that he said um
I'm pretty sure it's in the documentary
called The Notorious, which again, he
did the whole Kanye thing where he's
like poor kid in Ireland. He's like in
collections, not paying his credit card
bill. I think he's working part time as
a plumber and somehow he had the the
foresight to to have a camera crew
follow him around, document his life
because he was just so convinced that he
was going to be the champion one day and
he's going to be one of the most
successful professional fighters of all
time. And it's interesting that some of
these people don't take their own advice
because they they get to to Daniel X's
point, they entertain the circus. They
go to the events, they start buying, you
know, loving the the material rewards,
the drugs, the women, all the stuff that
comes with, you know, success. And
one of my personal heroes is a guy named
James Dyson. One of the best days of my
life happened, I think it was last maybe
October, maybe November in New York
City. I got to spend a few hours with
James Dyson. I did an episode with him.
And the reason this was so important for
me, people like the vacuum cleaner guy,
like what the hell is you talking about?
It's like, no, no. Out of every single
biography and autobiography I've ever
read in my life. And I think as of
today, it's like 425 or something like
that cuz it correlates with the the
founders episodes I've done. If I if you
only read one book, it'd be his first
autobiography, which is called Against
the Odds, an autobiography by James
Dyson. Because it's not about today, you
fast forward, he's 78 years old. He owns
a 100% of one of the most successful
private companies in the world. He
wouldn't sell it. I had a friend that
tried to buy it. He he guessed my friend
that tried to buy it that if James would
sell it, fetch between 60 to 80 billion.
James has no outside shareholders.
That's 100% of it. My friend put a flyer
out to him saying, "We want to buy your
company." He paraphrased the response
that came back from Dyson, which was,
"Fuck you. This is a family heirloom.
It's not about the money.
>> He's a he's an engineer. He's a
designer. He's obsessed with the work
that he's doing." So, it's that book is
not about this. It's not the 78-year-old
James Dyson. It is the Dyson in his 30s
and mid-40s that is just failing for a
decade and a half over and over and over
again. 5,126 failed prototypes. The
5,127th one is the one that worked. It's
the James L that's going to bed cuz he's
working in a carriage house which I I
guess is like a garage in England. What
is a carriage house?
>> No idea. Never heard that.
>> I had to look it up. I thought it's in
the UK so I figured you know. So, it's
like a detached little workshop outside
your main house. I think it's in Bath,
England where he might where he is where
he's failing all day long. Walks inside,
passes his little his kids, gets into
bed, cries himself to sleep. Then his
kid is four, sees him failing. His kid
is seven, dad's still failing. His kid
is a teenager, dad is still a failure.
And so, the reason this was so important
to me is because I knew I wanted to
podcast. I knew I loved it more than
anything else. I have this irrational
love of podcasting that people make fun
of me for and I'm fine with, but I was
having no success. It was not that like
I wasn't making any money. It was I was
it was costing me money to do this. My
my savings went down every month and I
for some reason wouldn't quit. And one
of the reasons I don't think I quit is
because episode 25 the the very fir time
I read James Ice's book is I read this
book and I'm like, well, this guy
struggled for 14 years. Like I can give
it a go for a year. Went up being five
and a half. I didn't think it'd take
that long. But like just knowing that
story and rereading that book over and
over and over again, it just I was able
to relate to him. I was like, "He didn't
give up. Why do I have to give up?"
Like, do you know how good you're going
to feel if you get to the other side of
this? And I did have a lot of faith that
I would get to the other side of it. And
so
when you meet James Dyson though, like I
read his first autobiography at least
five times. I read the highlights from
that book hundreds of times. This is not
a joke. It's not I'm not exaggerating. I
read his second biography which he wrote
when he was in the 70s twice. I read he
has he wrote an encyclopedia when he was
like 45 or 50 about he's obsessed with
inventions. It's called a history of
great inventions. It literally like
somebody printed out a Wikipedia page of
like 200 um inventions with handcrolled
notes. I there's a picture of me and
James going through the book me showing
him like me annotating every single
thing.
>> And so be able to sit with him I thought
I understood him completely and there
was still this is why it's so powerful
to be able to talk to these people.
First of all, he sits across from you
and you realize that he's built he
doesn't he's not a he's not a absentee
executive. He does the work. He's he's
on the the manufacturing line. He's in
the engineering meetings. He's in design
meetings. So you sit across from him.
He's a very thin guy. His
fingers are probably twice as wide as
mine are. Why? Because he's been working
with his hands. Like if look at your
biceps like your How many curls did you
do to get those biceps? how many like
him tinkering with his hands that did
that he get he's got massive fingers
they don't fit the rest of his body
because it's like a lifetime of
tinkering it's incredible but then the
reason I say if you go to sleep on a win
you wake up with a loss is like most
people they have success then they're
like I [\h__\h] made it look at me I'm
the best and they forget it's the work
that got them there not them it's tied
to the megalomania thing where Dyson is
not like that at all I didn't understand
his organizing principle and so this is
what he said he said okay I pick up a
product right I look at it I think about
How can I make it better? I make it
better. I put it back down.
Short mile while later, pick it back up.
How can I make it better? I make it a
little bit better. Put it back down. And
he went through this over and over
again. I think he used a coffee cup in
in the episode. It's been, you know, 6
months. I don't remember. And he goes,
"And I just didn't I just did that for
45 years and never stopped." That's the
anecdote to the anecdote. I don't know
if that's the right word to going to
sleep on a win. He never slept on a win
because he likes the the activity
itself. He just he has an engineering
mind. Everything around him, he says it
doesn't torment him, but he'd see this
table. He's like, I think I could shave
off a little bit there. I could fix
that. I could do that. That's how his
brain just works and he just loves it.
He's like a giant puzzle. And that's I
think that's the way to do it where it's
like, man, if you just love the activity
for the sake of itself and you never
stop improving it. Like you're not going
to fall prey to the failures and
disasters of like a Kanye or a Conor
McGregor or any of these other people
you see.
>> It's fascinating that that was a quote
from Conor McGregor, somebody that's had
one of the biggest falloffs in history.
>> Yeah. Unfortunately. Yeah.
>> Did you know your gut controls your
energy, your recovery, how well you
absorb everything that you eat, and the
one nutrient that keeps it all running
properly is fiber? Well, it turns out
that 95% of Americans don't get enough
of it, which is why I'm such a huge fan
of Momen's Fiber Plus. Most fiber
supplements are a one-trick pony. One
type of fiber solving one part of the
problem. Fiber Plus is a threein-one
formula built to tackle digestion, gut
barrier strength, and blood sugar
stability all at once. I use this every
single day. It is kind of hard to get
enough fiber just through food alone.
And best of all, Momenus offers a 30-day
money back guarantee. So, you can buy
it, try it every single day for 29 days.
And if you don't love it, they will just
give you your money back. Plus, they
ship internationally. Right now, you can
get up to 35% off your first
subscription and that 30-day money back
guarantee by going to the link in the
description below or heading to
livemus.com/modernwisdom
and using the code modernwisdom
a checkout. Yeah, I I I've kind of been
obsessed thinking about the difference
between
what it feels like to have fallen off
and what it feels like to have never
made it. I I would rather never make it.
I am This is another thing where you're
surprised. Like I've talked to Michael
Dell about this, Daniel Eko about this,
Todd Graves, Brett Jacobs, like all
these every single person I just
mentioned is worth tens. Michael Dell is
worth like $200 million. And he's just
like it's not the love of success, it's
a fear of failure. It's like for me that
is my worst nightmare that like I I I do
mean that like I would rather never make
it than make it, right? And then lose
it. And so this is why I I I wanted to
say something earlier that you just you
just prompt this thought. It's like it's
weird because like I'll meet with like
young entrepreneurs a lot, right? And I
feel like the middle child because I'm
not my 20s anymore, but I'm not 70, you
know? And so I'm in both of these
worlds. And the advice I give to these
like 25 years old, I go, you should go
and spend some time with like a
65year-old, 70-year-old, like like try
to get an afternoon with Jimmy I who's
in his 70s who's seen everything in the
world or a James Dyson who's seen
everything in the world. Like we we have
this guest list that uh we want we want
to get and it's in reverse chronological
order by age because some of these guys
like I got to sit down with Charlie Mer,
never got to record a podcast with him.
Now it's that opportunity is gone. Same
thing. Got to sit down with Sam, never
got to a podcast with him. They have all
this knowledge and all you have to do is
just like sit down and they'll they
they're already down the path that
you're that you want to go on and
they'll say, "Hey, watch for that
pitfall there. What don't don't turn
right when this is going to happen to
you." Cuz you realize like everything
that happens to us is not us.
>> If somebody else was sitting in your
position, they'd be getting those DMs,
too.
>> Like they just would. It's not you. It's
the position that you're holding.
>> Um and yeah, I think it's like super
important. People say I have a fetish
for old people. I don't have a fetish
for old people. just like I I want to
avoid
the failure, the the the se the success
and then the decline in failure that you
see so over and over and over again.
>> There's this interview in 1999. Eminem
said, "I ain't in this for the money.
I'm in here for the respect. If I had a
trillion dollars and I fell off, I'd be
the most miserable person in the world."
He grew up in poverty, but he favored
status over money. He stayed he favored
skill set. So, what um he he has a line
that I think um fits into how I view my
own work. And he says, "A plaque and
platinum status is whack if I'm not the
baddest." And what he what he was saying
at that point in this is 2003 when I
think the Eminem show came out, 2002
maybe. And his whole point at that time
is like every rapper had the same goal.
I want to go platinum because then you
get a plaque. So that's a plaque and
platinum status is whack if not the
baddest. His contemporaries, his peers
were like, "I'm good because I sold a
million records. It means people I'm
popular and it means I'm making a lot of
money. And his thing is like I want to
be the best. I don't want to be the
biggest. I want to be the best. And this
is why you and I have talked about the
craft of podcasting so much
>> and about like we we had a 30-minute
discussion with George before we started
recording about like how do you pick
guests? How do you think about things?
Like we we obsessed with this stuff.
It's like I want to make something that
I could point to like I could tell my
Jeff Basil says this great line. He's
just like we're trying to build
something that we can tell our grandkids
about and such things are not meant to
be easy. So in his case like he should
be very proud of building Amazon. It's
one of the best companies ever created.
Right? I am very very proud of some of
the things that I have made and I have a
daughter. So my daughter is 14 now. I
just recorded this episode with Mr.
Beast which won't be out for several
months. Um but she was a huge fan so she
got to come with me and meet him. And
Mr. is a massive fan of my first
podcast, Founders. His Spotify rap,
he'll screenshot and send it to me. It's
like Founders is number one on there.
And for her, I'm very proud that
somebody she admires is saying, "Hey,
your dad's work is like really valuable
to me." And she came with me to record
with Todd Graves. She loves Canes and
she knows the Spotify like her favorite
app is Spotify and my friend uh runs her
favorite brand, Mad Happy. And all these
people are telling her like, "Your dad's
work is really important to my life. You
should be proud of him." That's like
that's worth more than money. It's worth
more than a million dollars or 10
million that you'd get if you sold 10
million or a million records.
>> I do think it's more addicting and it's
certainly more fulfilling to be admired
by people that you admire. And it's one
thing to just seek status. It's another
thing to seek money, but to seek status
and respect in the eyes of people who
you have judged to be worthy of
admiration
inside and I would say outside your
industry for sure. And even more
important inside.
>> Yeah. the fact
>> they have the highest amount of taste.
>> I think you opened the last episode we
did together. You're like, "Did you hear
my Q&A where I said you're the
podcasters podcaster?"
>> Correct.
>> It's like I And I do this to this day. I
go around and collect more data on
podcasting podcasting than anybody else.
I sh and we share it. We like we don't
hold anything. And in one case, uh I
remember my friends David and Ben who
did the acquired podcast. Uh I was on a
walk with David I don't know like 3
months ago in San Francisco. He's
actually taking me to the airport cuz
we're just good friends. And I had found
an idea from Rob Moore and Andrew
Huberman that I gave to them in terms of
like you have a skew, you have an asset
in your podcast that you're not
currently monetizing and it's very
valuable to advertisers and this is what
they might pay. And I told David this
idea and on the walk he's like hey by
the way thanks for that idea. We're
going to make $3 million from that idea
this year.
>> Mhm.
>> And it's just like
>> I stole the same thing from Rogan back
end of last year.
>> Yeah. Ex. Exactly. So like the point is
like it's all positive sum with us. It's
like uh I consider the the the
historical analogy for for me and you is
like the filmmakers, right? If you study
the early days when George Lucas and
Steven Spielberg and Francis Forcopla
and Brian Dealma and all these guys were
in their 20s, they were friends. They
hung out. They traded secrets. They
watched each other's movies. They gave
themselves feedback because at the end
of the day, if you go watch Stephen
Spielberg's Jaws today and George
Lucas's Star Wars tomorrow, what did
Stephen Spielberg lose? Nothing. What
did George Lucas lose? Nothing. It's
like all positive stuff. Kind of is
pointless doing the big journey thing if
you don't get to share it with people.
And if people are in tangential
industries or even in the same sort of
an industry, just being able to see the
impact that you've had on somebody that
you respect and admire and know that
hey, like that idea that was the reason
that David paid so much attention to
video. That was a little that was just
like a little a little contribution.
That nice ripple
>> our mutual friend John Kugan, right?
just they just had this phenomenal
acquisition uh with TPBN but well before
even that I've been working with John
and like talking about podcasting with
John for years before he even even
started TPBN and he was one of the first
viewers of the new show and he's just
like why are you guys only shooting on
three cameras? Why don't you shoot five?
And he explained why.
>> And then me and Rob made the change
immediately.
>> You should try seven. Seven.
>> There you go. But but we made but here
we made the the change immediately and
then we're all in a group chat together
and Rob had mentioned, you know, we we
had a good shot and I think John was
like, "Hey, this shot looks good or
whatever." You know, cuz again, it's
it's both, hey, you can approve here,
but this is also dope. Like, I like
this. And Rob's like, "Yeah, you're the
one that told us the idea." Yeah, thank
you. J, can you pull up on the main TV?
Can you just throw the profile shot of
me up so that David can look at why you
need seven? I'm going to explain to you.
I'm gonna commit you to two more two
more cameras. So, uh, we've always had
medium, tight, and then the wide to kind
of classic. I guess if you've only got
three, you're going wide, medium,
medium. But this shot where you go very
side on. It's beautiful.
>> It's really, really nice. And what you
can do, you can reverse frame it. We
haven't done it here, but if you move,
so in fact, I can do it. I can do it by
doing this. So, if I go like that there,
you actually end up with a complete
opposite framing. And uh that's used in
documentaries typically when there's
going to be a pivot in the story.
>> Yeah.
>> So someone's talking, someone's talking,
someone's talking, and then there is a a
moment where things are going to take a
turn for the worst or something. It's
the it's the uh the minor chord that
somebody plays on the guitar and you're
like, "Oh, something's about to happen."
And it just feels very intimate. So
that's why you need seven. Um
>> season 8 winner of The Biggest Loser was
this dude called Danny. Just to round
out the difference between having never
made it and having fallen off, I was
watching the documentary about The
Biggest Loser,
accusations of it being uh predatory and
bullying and and dangerous and people
were getting [\h__\h] cardiac arrests and
being held out of there. Probably a big
helicopter, I guess. And [laughter]
he said there is an extra special shame
when you feel being a failure. There is
an extra special shame you feel being a
failure after you've been a success. And
um yeah, I mean the there is a huge huge
ick that people have and this is going
back to what you said that some people
are just not built for success. Lewis
Kapaldi is like my canonical example of
this and I'm so glad that he actually
managed to fix his issue and come out
the other side of it. But he had all of
the singing ability to be this billions
and billions and billions of record
sales artist. And he didn't have the
constitution for a long time to be able
to handle the attention. And
so many people think that the problem,
the reason that they're not famous and
they're not where they want to be is
because they don't have enough talent.
to be in the camp of people who has
enough talent but lacks the constitution
to be able to handle the side effects of
being that talented. It just has to be
like it's got to be very uncomfortable.
>> I want to like also like I think we
should say something about like I don't
think success like I think you should
have an internal scorecard not an outer
scorecard. So what I mean by that is
like some people let society or other
people define what that they are
successful. So what I mean by that is
like not that I have less downloads in
the future. I don't even know how many
downloads I get. I don't care. It's what
I the definition of success that I use I
actually got from Steve Jobs which was
like did I make something I'm proud of.
That's that's it. As long as I keep
making things I'm proud of or if I the
alternative of this is like you know how
much time it takes to make a great
episode. the amount of prep that you
have to do. And for my other podcast,
like I have to read an entire book. The
danger there is that I give into the
circus, given to the distractions, say,
"Oh, I used to put in 30 hours of
reading. I can do like six or I can read
like the Cliffnos version and still be
as good." That is to me is like
when I consider myself a failure is like
I'm not I'm no longer making things that
I'm proud of. Now, you have to make
things you're proud of. And also the
other side of it is like you have to get
it to in front of people and there's
smart and dumb ways to do that but like
so there is another element.
>> It doesn't make sense to be the super
cool underground band that nobody
actually listens to. Oh, it's because
they don't get it. They're not
sophisticated enough. I think eventually
you need to listen to the market. You're
like you can be as proud as you want of
the thing that you do, but your opinion
in terms of taste might not be on the
money. you there's a great line from
David Olgvi who is one of the greatest
advertising agency founders in history
and he says you can't save souls in an
empty church
>> and if you feel that modern wisdom is
good for people then you have a moral
obligation to get it to as many people
as possible if you truly believe that
which I think you do I truly believe
that people that are interested in
building a business creating a product
changing their lives in some manner
which is what the the word
entrepreneurship it's French for has
ideas entrepreneur is has ideas and does
them so that's why I consider podcaster
an entrepreneur, a filmmaker, an
entrepreneur, a person building Amazon
entrepreneur. It's all the same thing to
me. An athlete an entrepreneur. So,
somebody has an idea that they want to
see shape take shape and actually exist
in the world. Um, and so I I I would say
like if you believe that the work that
you're doing is good for the world, then
I would consider a moral obligation to
get it to as many people as possible.
David Sunra, ladies and gentlemen, dude,
you rule. I appreciate the heck out of
you. Where should people go to keep up
to date with everything you do?
>> Just search David Senna in whatever
podcast player or YouTube that you're
listening. Subscribe and listen.
>> Join us the podcast this podcast and
listen to Founders as well. All right.
Goodbye, my beauties.
>> Bye,
>> dude. Yes. Yes. You did it again. So
good.
>> Thank you very much for tuning in. If
you enjoyed that episode, another one
that I know you love. It's just here.